kimi no te ga hirogeta nani mo nai sora yo
Your hands spread out the vast and empty sky
君の手が広げた　何もない空よ
rikutsu no umi dake no kai wo asobeba
when you played with the seashells from the sea of reason
理屈の海だけの　解を遊べば
hodoite wa koboreta tagai no namida
Our tears welled up and fell
ほどいては溢れた　お互いのナミダ
kogashita kotoba usu kimagure
Our words of love were half in jest
降下した言葉・嘘・キマグレ
so i
So I
soul・art　リズムを奏でて
rhythm kanadete
play a song now
eyes slowly meets now
Our eyes slowly meet
合図をリングに繋ぐ
形だけのシステムと
katachi dake no system to
A system of pure shape
katami dake no majinai mo
A magic spell without power
形見だけの呪いも
tomo ni imu hajirai wo
We both detest shyness
逃亡人の恥じらい音
想像Drive　CarryOn　意地なTIRE
souzou daita kimi wo ijiru time
The times do not mean well with your dreams
誤解あるドアに　ゼロが眠りかけた
mukaeireru towa ni zero ga nemurikaketa
Eternity is signaling the end of all beginnings
ukeirerarenai hito to tenshi
Neither men nor angels can accept it
時計抱いた人と天使
towa ni naru kodomotachi
They are children before infinity
永久に飽くドール達
mata onaji kaze ni mogaite
fighting against the inevitable
また同じ風邪に　モガいて
一つ聞いてもいいですか
Can I ask you something?
Queen to F3.
f3　クイーン
Go ahead.
どうぞ
King to G7.
g7　キング
Should you really be sending me into battle?
僕を戦場に出してもいいんですか
Rook to E4.
e4　ルーク
If I die, the Deucalion's Aldnoah Drive will shut down.
僕が死んだら　デューカリオンのアルドノアは止まりますよ
理解しています
I'm aware of that.
Rook to D8.
d8　ルーク
しかし　その時はその時です
But we'll worry about it when the time comes.
界塚少尉は前線から退きたいと考えていますか
Would you like to be pulled back from the front lines, Second Lieutenant Kaizuka?
いいえ　僕は戦いに出ます
No.
I will fight.
f6　クイーン　チェック
Queen to F6.
Check.
King to F6. King takes queen.
クイーンを取って　f6　キング
なら意見は一致しています
We're on the same wavelength, then.
Bishop to E5.
e5　ビショップ　チェック
Check.
モニターに出します
I'll put it on the monitor.
今の手は君が考えたのですか
Did you come up with that move?
Or was it that analytical engine of yours?
それとも　そのアナリティカル・エンジンが
7:3くらいで僕です
About 70% of it was my idea.
7:3くらい
70%?
使っていない脳細胞にタスクを振り分けて処理の効率化を試してるんです
I'm trying to multi-thread between it and my brain to minimize idle time.
なのでデバイスからの提案であると同時に　自分の考えでもあるんです
So while this move can be traced back to the implant,
it is also based on my own ideas.
This ship and all aboard it owe their lives to you.
我々もこの船も君に救われた命です
If you want to fight, then we will support you as best we can.
君が戦いたいのなら　それを支えるのも良いと思っています
僕はそこまで特別な人間ではありません
I'm not as good as you make me out to be.
追加採取した姫殿下の血液を使って
Were you aware that we carried out activation experiments with blood samples from the princess?
アルドノアの起動実験が行われた事は聞いていますか
g5　キング
King to G5.
結果は失敗　彼らは起動条件を満たせなかった
They failed.
Blood alone could not replicate the activation factor.
少尉はかなり特殊なケースと言えます
You're a unique case.
姫殿下の救命処置の際にうつった
The activation factor infected you
when you resuscitated the princess,
感染した起動因子が王族の血液に触れ活性化した
and it was activated when you
came into contact with royal blood.
We've learned much about Aldnoah and their Cataphracts in the ten-odd months that have passed.
ここ十数ヶ月で
我々はアルドノアと彼らのカタフラクトについて多くの情報を得ました
しかし依然として　彼我の戦力差は圧倒的です
That said, the difference in power
between them and us is still immense.
It's anyone's guess as to
whether we can actually win.
このまま戦い続けて勝てるかどうか
ならば界塚少尉
But at this point, Second Lieutenant Kaizuka,
I'm going all in on you.
私は君にかけたい
g7 ビショップ
Bishop to G7.
投了しますか
Do you resign?
今の手はあなた？それとも左目？
Was that your move?
Or was it your eye's?
ご想像にお任せします
Whichever you'd like it to be.
さすがにタルシスでも そこまで遠い未来は見えないか
I suppose not even the Tharsis
can see that far into the future.
頼む
Carry on.
はっ
Yes, sir.
Welcome back, Sir Slaine.
おかえりなさいませ　スレイン様
ハークライトさんが計算してくれた範囲に　集弾させました
I fired rounds into the orbit you calculated.
Now all we can do is hope they won't be thrown off by unexpected winds.
後は余計な風の影響を受けない事を祈りましょう
Oh, I thought I smelled something foul.
何か臭うと思えば　犬が紛れ込んておるぞ
Seems a stray dog has wandered in.
And a rather mangy one at that.
しかも　随分と薄汚れた
ここに何の用だ
Why are you here?
これはバルークルス伯爵　マリルシャン伯爵
Count Barouhcruz, Count Marylcian.
私も参戦したく馳せ参じました
I came here that I might join the battle as well.
Terran dog.
地球の犬め
Let me remind you of your place.
生意気な口を
Count Saazbaum?
ザーツバルム卿
このスレイン･トロイヤードは我が家臣
Slaine Troyard here is my retainer.
粗相があれば謝罪しよう
I apologize for any offense he may have caused.
しかしいわれなき仕打ちであれば
Should he be mistreated for no reason, however,
マリルシャン卿　容赦はせぬぞ
you should not expect my mercy, Count Marylcian.
地球人を飼うだけなら酔狂で許されよう
If you wish to keep a Terran dog,
that is your business.
だが騎士に取り立てるなど　些か戯れがすぎるのではないか
But promoting him to knighthood
is carrying the joke too far.
バルークルス卿　我が家臣について貴公に口を出される筋合いはない
Count Barouhcruz, you have no right to opine on the treatment of my retainers.
しかし　共に戦うとなれば　別の話
We have every right when it is we who must fight alongside him!
How could anyone march to battle with someone who could betray them at any moment?
いつ裏切るとも分らぬ者とともに　戦場など出られませぬ
ならば　この場で私を斬ってください
If that is your concern,
please strike me down here and now.
あなたの言う通りです
It is as you say.
このまま戦場に出ると
If we go to war together,
you will surely betray me before long.
私の方が後ろから斬られかねません
貴様
You wretch!
Men!
諸君
聞かれよ諸君
Hearken, all who hear me!
ヴァース皇帝の庇護の元　今この場において
Under the laws of His Imperial Majesty, I adopt Slaine Troyard as my son.
スレイン･トロイヤードを我が息子とする
この場に同席された諸君が証人である
All present are my witnesses!
My lord...
伯爵
立て　スレイン
Arise, Slaine.
今日からそなたは我が息子だ
As of this moment, you are my son.
これでも手を出すおつもりか　マリルシャン卿
Would you raise your hand against him even now,
Count Marylcian?
If such is the extent of your fondness for him, so be it.
貴公にそこまでの覚悟がおありなら　よいでしょう
しかし僅かでもおかしなマネをすれば
But if I should ever detect the
slightest hint of suspicious behavior,
容赦なく斬る
I will not hesitate to kill him.
申し訳ありません
I apologize.
私のせいでこのようなことに
You did not have to do that for me.
よい　前々から決めていたことだ
Do not worry.
I made my decision some time ago.
Should I fall in battle, I need an heir to succeed me.
我も戦地に赴く　後継者は決めておかねばならぬ
今後は我を父と思うがよい
From now on, think of me as your father.
おめでとうございます　スレイン様
Congratulations, Sir Slaine.
伯爵家後継ぎ
Becoming the Count's heir has brought you
one step closer to your dream.
これでまた一歩夢にお近づきになりましたね
Please, Mister Harklight.
止してください　ハークライトさん
僕に夢なんてありませんよ
I have no dreams.
もう間もなくですね
It won't be long now.
Yes.
はい
あなたはどちらが勝つと思いますか　エデルリッゾ
Who do you think will win, Eddelrittuo?
そ…それはもちろん　我らヴァース帝国軍が勝利するに決まっております
Th-That's clear! Our glorious Vers Army, of course!
あら　いいの
Oh? Do you really want that?
連合軍にはお友達の船もいるんでしょう
Isn't there a UE ship on which you have friends?
Who told you that?
何をおっしゃいます　地球に友など…
I have no friends amongst the Terrans!
そう　では賭けましょうか
Really?
Let's bet on who'll win, then.
Bet?
賭け…
ヴァース帝国の勝利に
What should I wager on Vers' victory?
そうね　例えば　お姉さまの命とか
How about...
my sister's life?
冗談よ
I'm only joking.
お姉さまは今どんな夢を見ているのかしらね
I do wonder what she's dreaming of right now, though.
韻子を見ませんでした
Have you seen Inko?
She's probably at the EM catapult.
電磁カタパルトじゃねぇ　多分ライエちゃんと一緒
With that Rayet chick.
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます
Don't get lost, now.
迷子になんなよ
はい
'Kay.
A tracksuit?!
ジャージ
祐太郎ちゃんガツガツしすぎ
Keep it in your pants, Yutie.
タルシス　能力の詳細は不明
The Tharsis. Details on its abilities are unknown.
攻撃回避率が高いとの報告がある
However, reports state its rate of evasion is high.
確認されている搭乗者は…
Pilot confirmed...
スレイン･トロイヤード
as Slaine Troyard.
地球に来る時　親しい地球人にもらったお守りです
A good-luck charm I received when leaving for Earth
from a Terran dear to me.
It's flying!
空を飛ぶ生き物
スレインの言った通り
It's just like Slaine said.
奴も神経接続された アナリティカル・エンジンを積んでいるのか
Is he outfitted with a neuro-linked analytical engine too?
Fair point. But there's too little data.
確かに…　でもデータが少なすぎる
He was dodging my attacks like he knew they were coming.
先読みをしているような避け方だった
それが本当なら　厄介だな
If that's true...
it makes things complicated.
独り言？
Talking to yourself?
自分と話してた
I was talking with myself.
Is there a difference?
だから　独り言だろ
八本足の神獣　スレイプニールを操る軍神オーディンは
The warrior god Odin, rider of the legendary eight-legged Sleipnir,
ミーミルの泉の水を飲み　膨大な知識を授かる
drank of Mímir's well and was
endowed with great wisdom.
But the price he paid for
that wisdom was his left eye.
が その代償として自らの左目を失った
北欧神話
That's Norse mythology.
Wow, you knew all that?
物知りだね
You making fun of me?
お前　俺のことバカにしてんだろ
ロシアでの戦いの後さぁ　船を降りようと思ってんだ
After the battle in Russia,
I was gonna abandon ship.
怖くなっちまってさ
I was pissing myself.
But then it hit me: if I did, how would I ever look Okojo in the eye in the next world?
でもやっぱりそれじゃ　あの世でオコジョに顔向きできないよなって
Come to me if your steed ever gets ornery.
馬の調子が悪くなったら　いつでも言ってくれよ
I'll whip it back into shape.
速攻で直すからさ
頼りにしてるよ
Thanks. Will do.
Okay!
よし　出撃前に何か食べるか
Wanna get some food before you sortie?
We've still got time.
まだ少し時間あるし
No thanks.
やめとくよ
僕が撃たれた時　胃の中が空だったらしい
Apparently when I was shot,
my stomach was empty.
それで内容物で内臓が汚染されなくて　命が助かったって
The doctor said the lack of contamination to my organs from food saved my life.
Oh. Sure.
でもせっかくだし　お茶くらいなら
I'll still do tea, though.
リールのセレクトは
What are his reel selections?
1号から3号に　緊急用の10号を入れて
He's got a #1 through #3 and an
emergency-use #10 on either side.
右と左に一つずつ
So it's specced out for high-G pivots?
高G旋回仕様だね
細く長くは性分じゃない
Long, thin wires aren't suited for that.
There you are!
あ　いたぁ
Oh, Team Deucalion!
チームデューカリオン
The famous Aldnoah unit, huh?
噂のアルドノア部隊か
I hear one of you is a Martian.
火星人なんだってな
Don't cause trouble for us on the battlefield, okay, girls?
戦場で足引っ張ってくれるなよ　お嬢ちゃんたち
What was their problem? Assholes.
何なのあいつら　最低
They weren't wrong.
でも間違ってない
火星人はみんな敵
All Martians are the enemy.
I should know.
私が一番わかってる
You're so cute, Rayet.
可愛いな　ライエは
ツンツンしちゃって
Trying to act all sour.
What?
You can let the sweetness show too, you know.
もっとデレてくれていいのよ
What're you talking about?
何言ってるの
Want some candy?
飴ちゃん舐める
ぶっ飛ばすわよ
Want a knuckle sandwich?
30分後に防空域が接触します
Entering the defensive area in thirty minutes.
出撃願います
Please launch.
Good luck, sir.
いざ　ご武運を
How fares my steed?
我が愛馬は
調整すべて終了しました
The adjustments have been completed.
ディオスクリアII　出るぞ
Dioscuria Two, to launch!
Slaine Troyard, launching in the Tharsis.
スレイン･トロイヤード　タルシス発進します
ステイギス隊　出撃
Stygis Platoon, launching!
火星カタフラクト隊　接近
Incoming Martian Cataphract platoon!
Calling all forces!
全隊に通達　作戦開始
Commence operation!
Message from HQ!
司令本部より入電　作戦開始命令っす
Commence operation!
Deucalion, launch.
デューカリオン　発進
当艦は遊撃隊として　攻撃隊を支援する
We are to act as a commando unit and support our attacking forces.
全艦　戦闘態勢
All hands, prepare for battle.
Our Cataphracts are launching from Trident Base.
トライデント基地より　当艦の艦載機が発進します
Mustang 11, cleared for launch!
マスタング１１　クリアードフォーランチ
ラジャー
Roger. Mustang 11, cleared for launch!
マスタング１１　クリアードフォーランチ
Blast off!
ブラスト
Blast off.
ブラスト・オフ
Target merge. Commencing attack!
ターゲット・マージ　攻撃開始
攻撃　来ます
Enemy fire!
Not yet! They can't hit us in this wind, anyway! Don't fire until you see the whites of their eyes!
まだだ　どうせ　この風の中では命中しない
よく引きつけて狙え
よく引きつけて狙う　よく引きつけて狙う
The whites of their eyes... The whites of their eyes...
My umbrella's been blown away!
傘をやられた
Mustang 11!
マスタング１１
I'm okay!
大丈夫
But this debris isn't good!
でもデブリが…　振動で照準が合わない
I can't line up a shot with all this shaking!
Mustang 00, supporting.
マスタング００　援護する
Inaho!
伊奈帆
Where's your umbrella?
ちょっと　傘は？
小雨だよ　必要ない
It's only a drizzle.
I don't need it.
Stop pulling crazy stunts!
無茶しないでってば
どうせ　ドックファイトじゃ使えないよ
It wouldn't be any use in a dogfight, anyway.
重力偏向を推測　データ補正よし
Calculating changes in gravity.
Data compensation, ready.
Fire.
ファイア
Commence attack!
攻撃開始
Damn Martians!
この…
ワイヤー・スイングバイで旋回　戦闘区域に帰還
Pivoting via wire swing-by.
Returning to battle zone.
#3, shoot.
3号シューティング
旋回終了まで　後４秒
Four seconds to pivot completion.
Three.
３　２　１　リリース
Two.
One.
Release.
界塚伊奈帆
Kaizuka Inaho!
Slaine Troyard!
スレイン・トロイヤード
マリネロス基地　最接近まで　後３０秒
Thirty seconds till Marineros Base is in range.
Main cannons ready to fire.
主砲　発射準備よし
Message to all platoons:
remove yourself from our line of fire!
各隊に通達　射線上から退避せよ
ライエ
Rayet!
こちら　ラインランダー２２
This is Rhinelander 22!
Damn, this guy's persistent!
チクショウ　ケツを取られた
Acknowledged.
了解　マスタング２２　援護する
Mustang 22, assisting.
火星人
The Martian!
Marineros Base now in range.
マリネロス基地　射程に入りました
射線上に友軍機なし
No friendly units in line of fire.
Fire main cannons!
主砲発射
マリネロス基地　離隔に入ります
Marineros Base is breaking off.
Send the disengagement order to all attacking and commando platoons! Switch to defense!
攻撃隊及び遊撃隊に撤退命令
防衛に回せ
Inaho, we've been ordered to disengage! Come back!
伊奈帆　撤退命令よ　戻って
伊奈帆
Inaho!
正確な射撃ですね
That's some deadeye shooting, all right.
やっぱり　奴も予測している
I knew it. He's predicting the shots too.
１号旋回
#1, pivot.
You're mine the second you poke your head out of those rocks.
岩石から姿を現した瞬間を狙う
岩石から姿を現した瞬間を狙ってくる
He'll attack as soon as I come out.
座標確認　着弾まであと２分
Coordinates confirmed. Two minutes to impact.
Let's do this.
行くぞ
ファイア
Fire.
当たった？
I hit him?
あれは…
Is that...
Are you all right, Slaine?
大丈夫か　スレイン　下がっておれ
I shall take over.
いえ　まだ戦えます
I can still fight.
Don't push yourself.
無理をするな
That orange unit and I have some unfinished business to settle.
オレンジ色　奴には借りがある
バリアの隙間か　位置は変えさせてもらった
Looking for the gap in my barrier?
I took the liberty of relocating it.
飛べ　我が眷属よ
Fly, my children!
エネルギージョイント 接続
Connecting to energy joints.
ブレードフィールド　展開
Activating blade field.
En garde.
抜刀
逃がさぬ
I won't let you escape.
伊奈帆　援護する
Inaho!
I'll cover! You just get out of here!
逃げて　伊奈帆
Stay back, Inko!
来ちゃダメだ　韻子
No!
いや
Yes!
いいんだ
その位置がいい
Don't move.
Prepare yourself, Terran!
覚悟しろ
地球人
右キックスラスター　投棄よし
Right kick thruster jettisoned!
Fire!
ファイア
That location isn't absorbing the flames!
It's the gap in his barrier!
炎が吸い込まれない
バリアの隙間
You're not getting away!
逃がすか
スレイン
Slaine!
What?
何
A high-speed debris cluster.
高速デブリの群れだ
My 3D Doppler radar detected a rapidly approaching cloud.
三次元ドップラーレーダーに　急速に接近する雲の反応があった
ありがとう　韻子
Thank you, Inko.
One split second later,
あと一歩遅かったら
僕も巻き込まれていた
and I would have been hit by it too.
Impossible!
バカな　たかがデブリ如きに　このディオスクリアが
How could my Dioscuria be felled by mere debris?!
デブリではありません
That wasn't debris.
銃弾です
It was bullets.
I fired them in advance of the battle.
開戦前に銃撃しておいたんです
地球の衛星軌道を回って
I aimed them so that they'd wrap around the Earth
and pass through that very spot.
ちょうど今　その辺りに着弾するように
スレイン
Slaine?
This was a trap I originally devised to defeat Kaizuka Inaho.
元々は界塚伊奈帆を倒すための罠だったんです
次元バリアの無効化がネックでしたが
It didn't factor in your dimensional barrier, of course,
but I figured if anyone could disable it, he could.
彼なら上手くやってくれると思った
スレイン
Slaine!
Shut up!
黙れ
僕があなたに忠誠を誓うと　本気で信じたのですか
Did you honestly believe I would swear loyalty to you?
アセイラム姫殿下に引き金を引いたあなたを…
To the man who pulled the trigger on Princess Asseylum?
Did you think I would just forgive and forget?
僕が許すと思ったのですか
そろそろ第二波が来ます
My second volley's almost here.
さようなら
Farewell,
Father.
お父さん
悪くない
Not bad.
私はこの日 二人目の父を失った
Today, I lost my father for a second time.
共にヴァース帝国の繁栄に尽くした偉大な人物だった
Yet he was also a great man who gave everything for the glory of the Vers Empire.
私は今ここに父たちの遺志を継ぎ
I swear, here and now, to carry on my fathers' wills and fight for an even greater Vers future!
ヴァース帝国のさらなる隆興のため 戦うことを決意する
Hear me, my lords of the Orbital Knights.
ヴァース軌道騎士の諸侯よ
Now is no time for petty infighting.
今は互いに争っている時ではない
崇高なるヴァース帝国の騎士として
As knights of the noble Vers Empire, is it not our duty to join forces and eliminate the rebels of Earth?
手を取り合い　地球の反抗勢力を殲滅しようではないか
In the name of Her Highness Asseylum Vers Allusia,
アセイラム・ヴァース・アリューシア姫殿下の名のもとに
let us drop the hammer of justice on those who defy us!
我らヴァース帝国に歯向かう地球人に制裁を
He isn't lying.
あいつ　嘘をついていない
Huh?
Our princess remains on the moon base,
waiting for the right time...
アセイラム姫殿下は月面基地にて時を待っておられる
やっぱり　生きてるんだ
I knew she was alive.
Brilliant speech, sir.
大儀　お疲れ様にございます
ハークライトさんは第三階層のご出身でしたね
Mister Harklight, you were born into the third class, right?
Yes, sir.
はい
They were poor and could not hope for much,
身分が低く　貧困にありながら
父と母は苦労して私を育て
but my parents endured much during my upbringing
and spared no expense in ensuring
that I could serve the Orbital Knights.
あらゆる伝手を頼って軌道騎士の元へ送り出してくれました
だからこそ　スレイン様
It is for that reason I have the
utmost respect for you, Sir Slaine,
地球人でありながら　爵位を得るまでに至ったあなたを
who rose to the rank of count
despite your Terran heritage.
私は心から　ご尊敬　申し上げるのです
ここからは僕たちの時代です
The era to come will belong to people like us.
行くぞ　ハークライト
Follow me, Harklight.
はい
Of course,
Count Slaine Saazbaum Troyard.
スレイン・ザーツバルム・トロイヤード伯爵
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听:天天大魔王&Archer   翻译:mam&郝郝  校对:安少&zwx   时间轴:阿水   压制:河蟹
bokutachi wa samayoeru mirai
We are a future of dubious likelihood
僕たちは　彷徨える未来
窮屈な空に　ヒカリを探している
kyuukutsu na sora ni
We look to the oppressive sky
hikari wo sagashiteiru
in search of light
furueru te wa muryoku de
Our trembling hands are powerless
震える手は無力で
叫びはまだ遠くて
sakebi wa mata tookute
Our screams reach no one
dakedo tobu koto wo
But we will never be afraid
たけど飛ぶことを恐れてはいられない
osorete wa irarenai
of flying
永遠じゃなくても　完璧じゃなくても
eien ja nakutemo
We don't need eternity
kanpeki ja nakutemo
We don't need perfection
senaka-awase no sekai wo
We live in two related
背中合わせの世界を　真っ直ぐ生きてゆく
massugu ikiteyuku
but wildly different worlds
nando kizu tsuitemo
No matter the wounds we receive
何度傷ついても　何度間違えても
nando machigaetemo
and the mistakes we make,
unmei sae tobikoete yukou
we will overcome fate
運命さえ飛び越えていこう
kono sora no hate made
Until the skies above us end
この宙の果てまで
hajimari wo shinjite
we will believe in the genesis of a better life
創造を信じて